peoplelookup.com 2016-06-27

# PeopleLookup People Search - Public Records, Background Checks & More.

PeopleLookup.com Privacy Policy

Effective January 15, 2016

PeopleLookup.com respects your right to privacy and we are committed to protecting it. This policy discloses our information practices, including what type of personal information we gather and track, how we use this personal information, with whom we share the personal information, the choices available to you regarding our use of your personal information, and how you can access and update this information. Please keep in mind that this Policy applies to all PeopleLookup.com brands, products and services that do not have a separate privacy policy. If you have questions or concerns regarding this Policy, you should contact us at [privacy@peoplelookup.com](mailto:privacy@peoplelookup.com).

Personal Information

In general, you can visit us without telling us who you are and without giving any personal information about yourself. However, you may choose to give us personal information in a variety of situations. For example, you may want to give us information such as your name and address, phone number or e-mail address so we may correspond with you, process an order, or provide you with a subscription or service. You may give us your credit card details to buy a product or service from us, or provide us a description of your education and work experience in connection with a job opening at PeopleLookup.com for which you wish to be considered. The purpose of this Policy is to inform you of how we will use your information, before you provide it. If you tell us that you do not want us to use this information in this manner or to make further contact with you beyond fulfilling your requests, we will respect your wishes. If you give us personal information about somebody else, such as a spouse or associate, we will assume that you have their permission to do so.

How to Remove your Information from the PeopleLookup.com Public Records Databases

Public records are available from the official public records custodian or repository to anyone who requests them. In addition to public records, personal information may be publicly or commercially available. Publicly available information consists of online and offline information that is generally available but is not maintained by a government agency, such as names, addresses and telephone numbers of individuals and businesses, professional licensing and trade organization information, press releases and newspaper articles and content from blogs or social networking sites. Commercial records consist of information that is maintained by enterprises and is available for purchase, such as marketing and telemarketing lists, phone connect and disconnect information, and business profile data.

As a courtesy we enable you to opt out your personal information from our databases. What this means is that your name as it appears in a particular record and the associated identifying information such as your address and phone number will be suppressed if you request this in the manner described below. However, please note that any time your identifying information appears in a public record or in a publicly or commercially available manner, in a way that is different from the particular record you opted out, it may again appear in our databases. For example, if your address or area code changes, your new information -- including other associated identifying information may again appear unless you opt out the new record. Similarly, if the way in which your name or address appears in a record differs from a record you opted out (e.g., "Michael" instead of "Mike," or "1212 Second AVE NE" instead of "1212-2nd Avenue Northeast"), we may include the differing record. Please also note that there may be more than one record in our databases associated with your personal information. Opting out one particular record will not opt out other record(s). An opt-out will apply from processing date forward; any report purchased prior to your opt-out will still be available to the purchaser thereof in accordance with the terms of our service. In addition to PeopleLookup.com, there are many other companies offering public records search services, and your request that we opt out your information from our databases will not prevent your information from appearing on these other services.

You can submit an opt-out request via fax or postal mail. Regardless of which method you choose, in order for us to suppress your personal information from appearing in our databases, we need to verify your identity. To do this, we need proof of identity, consisting of either:

  * a copy of a government-issued ID with any photo or ID number crossed out. Examples: driver's license, U.S. passport, U.S. military ID card, state-issued ID card, or employee ID card from a state agency, or

We will only use this information to process your opt out request.

In addition to your proof of identity, please include the following so we can accurately identify your records:

  * Name
  * Date of Birth
  * Address

Here is the contact information for submitting your request:

**Fax** | (425) 974-6194  
---|---  
**Mail** | P.O. Box 4145  
Bellevue, WA 98009-4145  
  
Your information will be removed from our database in approximately 7-14 days. Opt-out requests must be submitted to us individually by the subject of a particular record. Bulk opt-out requests will not be fulfilled.

**How we Use and Share Personal Information**

The following paragraphs describe in more detail how we may use the personal information you provide to us and with whom we may share it.

_Fulfilling your Transaction Request_. If you request something from us, for example, a product or service, a callback, or specific marketing materials, we will use the information you provide to fulfill your request. To help us do this, we will share information with service providers to help us bring you the products and services we offer, either directly as the provider of such product or service, or indirectly such as credit card gateways, fraud detection services, email service providers, outsourced Customer Care providers or postal service providers. These third parties are prohibited from using your personal information for any other purpose. We also require these third parties to maintain your personal information in the strictest confidence.

In addition, we gather certain information automatically (including cookies and log files). This information includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp and click stream data. We may combine this automatically collected log information with other information we collect about you. We do this to improve the services we offer you, improve marketing, analytics, or website functionality.

We use cookies to identify users and repeat visitors to our website (but not in the PeopleLookup.com app). Users can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level. If you reject cookies, you may still use our website, but your ability to use some features or areas of our website may be limited.

We, and our partners, affiliates, or analytics or service providers, may use tracking technologies such as cookies, beacons, scripts, and tags to analyze trends, administer this website, track users' movements around this website, and gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies from these companies on an individual or aggregated basis. The cookies we use for these purposes and to fulfill your transaction request may contain your email address. One of our analytics providers, Adobe, offers the ability for you to opt-out of tracking by following the instructions here: <http://www.d1.sc.omtrdc.net/optout.html>.

Third parties with whom we partner to provide certain features on our website (but not in the PeopleLookup.com app) or to display advertising based on your web browsing activity use Local Storage (HTML5) to store content information and preferences. Various browsers may offer their own management tools for removing HTML5.

_Communications from Us_. When you request something from us, we will send you transactional emails related to your service request. You cannot opt out of receiving these communications. However, you can opt in to receive promotional emails from us. If you later choose to opt out of receiving these emails, you can unsubscribe by clicking on the link included in the email or logging in to your account and changing your preferences.

_Marketing Use_. The information you provide to us, as well as information that we capture described above, may also be used by us and selected third party service providers for marketing purposes related to our products and services. We do not share, sell, rent, or trade your personal information with third parties for their marketing purposes.

Third Party Advertisers

We may use third-party advertising companies to serve ads on our behalf. These companies may employ cookies and action tags (also known as single pixel gifs or web beacons) to measure advertising effectiveness. Any information that these third parties collect via cookies and action tags is completely anonymous. If you would like more information about this practice and your choices, click here. They may also use technologies such as cookies to gather information about your activities on this website and other websites in order to provide you advertising based on your browsing activities and interests. If you wish not to have this information used for the purpose of serving you interest-based ads, you may opt out by clicking [here](http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/). Please note this does not opt you out of being served ads. You will continue to receive generic ads.

Other Voluntary Information

We display personal testimonials and other endorsements of satisfied customers. With your consent, we may post your testimonial along with your name. If you wish to update or delete your testimonial, you can contact us at [privacy@peoplelookup.com](mailto:privacy@peoplelookup.com).

PeopleLookup.com Human Resources

In connection with an PeopleLookup.com job application or inquiry, you may provide us with information about yourself, such as a resume or curriculum vitae. We use this information throughout PeopleLookup.com and our affiliates for the purpose of employment consideration or otherwise responding to your inquiry. Unless you request that we don't, we may keep the information for future consideration.

Data Retention and Disclosures Required By Law

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active and/or as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements. We reserve the right to disclose your personal information as required by law and when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or comply with a judicial proceeding, court order or legal process. If we are involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of our assets, you will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our website of any change in uses of your personal information or choices you may have regarding your personal information.

Links to Non-PeopleLookup.com Websites

We may include links to other websites whose privacy practices may differ from ours. If you submit personal information to any of those websites, your information is governed by their privacy policies. We encourage you to carefully read the privacy policy of any website you visit.

We use Social Media Features (such as the Facebook Like button) and Widgets (such as the Share This button or interactive mini-programs). These features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted by us directly. Your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

Children

PeopleLookup.com products and services are not intended for children under the age of 13. We do not knowingly publish information concerning anyone under the age of 13. If you know of information in our databases concerning anyone under the age of 13, or have other concerns about children's privacy, please send an email to us at [privacy@peoplelookup.com](mailto:privacy@peoplelookup.com).

Information Security

The security of your personal information is important to us. When you enter sensitive information (such as your name, email address, credit card number and/or social security number) on our registration or order forms, we encrypt that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL).

We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet or method of electronic storage is 100% secure, however. Therefore, while we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

Access to your Account

If you would like to update your personal information in your account such as your name, address or email address, you can do so by logging in to your account and updating your personal information.

If you wish to cancel your account, or request that we no longer use your information to provide you services, contact us at [privacy@peoplelookup.com](mailto:privacy@peoplelookup.com).

Enforcement

We regularly review our compliance with this Policy. Please feel free to direct any questions or concerns regarding this Policy to [privacy@peoplelookup.com](mailto:privacy@peoplelookup.com) or by writing us at Privacy c/o PeopleLookup.com, 500 108th AVE NE, 16th Floor, Bellevue, WA 98004. It is our policy to contact the complaining user regarding his or her concerns.

Changes to this Policy

We reserve the right to modify this Policy at any time, so please review it frequently. A changed Policy will be indicated by the "Effective" date at the top of this Agreement. In addition, if we make any material changes we will notify you by means of a notice on our website prior to the change becoming effective.
